The Deserter is a western, drama film directed by Thomas H. Ince.
A deserting soldier encounters a wagon train of settlers.
When they are faced with an Indian attack, he risks court
martial to return to the Army post for help.
The Deserter, played by Francis Ford.
The Captain, played by William Clifford.
The Colonel, played by J. Barney Sherry.
The Colonel's Daughter, played by Lillian Christy.
The Deserter is a 1912 American silent black-and-white two-reel
Western film written and directed by Thomas H.
It was released March 15, 1912 and starred Francis Ford and Ethel Grandin.
The film was screened in December 2006 at the Museum of Modern Art
in New York, as part of a retrospective on Thomas H.
The film is available at the Library of Congress.
The tone is emotional.